Finding Aid for Harlan Henthorne Hatcher Papers
Bentley Historical Library
- Pre-and Post-Presidential Files
  - Retirement, 1968-1998
    - Speeches
      - Environment
        - "Urbanization of the Great Lakes," Clements Library, May 1969 (Box 72)
        - "Megalopolis, Planned or Unplanned," Centre College of Kentucky, Circa, November 1969 (Box 72)
        - "The Great Lakes Megalopolis," 18th Annual Construction Conference, November 20, 1969 (Box 72)
        - "Problems in Our Society: The Air," Panel Discussion, n.d (Box 72)
        - Miscellaneous, 1969-1985 (Box 72)
      - Michigan and Ohio History
        - Pioneering Spirit Symposium, Northwest Technical College, Archibold, OH, May 1975 (Box 72)
        - "American Frontiers," Baldwin-Wallace College, October 26, 1975 (Box 72)
    - Travels
      The Travels subseries contains documentation of two vacations Dr. Hatcher took during his retirement: The Alumni World Tour in 1968 and a trip to China and Japan in 1977.
      - Alumni World Tour, February-March 1968 (Box 72)
      - China and Japan, August 1977 (Box 72)
- Audio and Visual Materials
  The Audio And Visual Materials series (.7 linear ft.) is divided into two subseries: Photographs and Audio Recordings of Speeches.
  - Photographs
    The Photographs series is arranged into the following categories: Portraits, Writings, Ohio State University, U.S. Navy and U.S. Army, The University of Michigan, Organizations, and Immediate Family.
    - Portraits of Harlan Hatcher (Box 72)
      (see also oversize folder Ac)
    - Writings
      - The Buckeye Country (Box 72)
      - Lake Erie (Box 72)
      - The Western Reserve (Box 72)
    - Ohio State University (Box 72)
    - U.S. Navy and U.S. Army, 1944-1960 (Box 72)
    - The University of Michigan
      - Awards
        - "Professors Extraordinary," Universidad Nacional de Mexico, 1959 (Box 72)
          (from album)
        - Unidentified Banquet Honoring Harlan Hatcher (Box 72)
          (from UM insignia album)
        - Harlan Hatcher Receiving Honorary Degrees from Other Universities (Box 72)
      - World Leaders
        - President Gerald Ford, 1952; 1993 (Box 72)
        - President Lyndon Johnson, 1964 (Box 72)
        - President Kazuo Okochi, Japan, 1965 (Box 72)
        - President Sukarno, Indonesia, Circa, 1967 (Box 72)
      - Travels
        - Orient, January 1956 (Box 72)
        - Taiwan (Box 72)
        - Waseda University, Japan (Box 72)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 72)
      - Hill Auditorium and Michigan Union Ballroom Set Up for Inauguration, November 27, 1951 (Box 72)
      - North Campus Ground Breaking, 1952 (Box 72)
      - Building Dedication, 1955 (Box 72)
      - Giving Speeches; Giving or Receiving Degrees or Awards (Box 72)
      - From Album Featuring Hatcher Family (Box 72)
      - Board of Regents (Box 72)
        (see also photograph of HHH and Regent Roscoe Bonisteel and group portrait of regents, October 1953, in oversize folder Ac)
      - Miscellaneous Groups, 3 folders (Box 72)
    - Organizations
      - Detroit Edison Board of Directors (Box 72)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 72)
    - Immediate Family (Box 72)
  - Audio Recordings of Speeches
    The Audio Recordings of Speeches subseries contains two magnetic tapes: WIU Commencement Address, June 4, 1959; and Battelle Auditorium, January 14, 1970. There is also an audio cassette recording of a speech at Inglis House, about the Federal Writer's Project and The Ohio Guide, circa 1993.
    - Western Illinois University; Commencement Address, 1959 June 04; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips (Box 72)
      - [Part 1], [851647-SR-1-1]; (Harlan Hatcher giving the 1959 Western Illinois University commencement speech.)
        [Digitized audio files are only available in the Bentley Historical Library reading room on designated Bentley Library computers.]
    - Audio Cassette, Inglis House, On the Federal Writer's Project and The Ohio Guide, Circa, 1993 (Box 72)